export default {
  id: 'low_1006_2_1a',
  name: '상용한자(2학년-1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '東', answer: ['동녘 동', 'ひがし', 'とう'] },
    { question: '西', answer: ['서녘 서', 'にし', 'せい、さい'] },
    { question: '南', answer: ['남녘 남', 'みなみ', 'なん、[な]'] },
    { question: '北', answer: ['북녘 북', 'きた', 'ほく'] },
    { question: '春', answer: ['봄 춘', 'はる', 'しゅん'] },
    { question: '夏', answer: ['여름 하', 'なつ', 'か、[げ]'] },
    { question: '秋', answer: ['가을 추', 'あき', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '冬', answer: ['겨울 동', 'ふゆ', 'とう'] },
    { question: '父', answer: ['아버지 부', 'ちち', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '母', answer: ['어머니 모', 'はは', 'ぼ'] },
    { question: '兄', answer: ['형 형', 'あに', 'けい、[きょう]'] },
    { question: '弟', answer: ['아우 제', 'おとうと', 'てい、[だい]、[で]'] },
    { question: '姉', answer: ['손위 누이 자', 'あね', 'し'] },
    { question: '妹', answer: ['누이 매', 'いもうと', 'まい'] },
    { question: '親', answer: ['친할 친', 'おや、した(しい)、した(しむ)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '友', answer: ['벗 우', 'とも', 'ゆう'] },
    { question: '自', answer: ['스스로 자', 'みずか(ら)', 'じ、し'] },
    { question: '分', answer: ['나눌 분', 'わ(ける)、わ(かれる)、わ(かる)、わ(かつ)', 'ぶん、ふん、ぶ'] },
    { question: '古', answer: ['옛 고', 'ふる(い)、ふる(す)', 'こ'] },
    { question: '今', answer: ['이제 금', 'いま', 'こん、きん'] },
    { question: '内', answer: ['안 내', 'うち', 'ない、[だい]'] },
    { question: '外', answer: ['바깥 외', 'そと、ほか、はず(す)、はず(れる)', 'がい、げ'] },
    { question: '前', answer: ['앞 전', 'まえ', 'ぜん'] },
    { question: '後', answer: ['뒤 후', 'のち、うし(ろ)、あと、おく(れる)', 'ご、こう'] },
    { question: '多', answer: ['많을 다', 'おお(い)', 'た'] },
    { question: '少', answer: ['적은 소', 'すく(ない)、すこ(し)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '強', answer: ['강할 강', 'つよ(い)、つよ(まる)、つよ(める)、し(いる)', 'きょう、ごう'] },
    { question: '弱', answer: ['약할 약', 'よわ(い)、よわ(る)、よわ(まる)、よわ(める)', 'じゃく'] },
    { question: '遠', answer: ['멀 원', 'とお(い)', 'えん、[おん]'] },
    { question: '近', answer: ['가까울 근', 'ちか(い)', 'きん'] },
    { question: '万', answer: ['일만 만', '일만', 'まん、ばん'] },
    { question: '牛', answer: ['소 우', 'うし', 'ぎゅう'] },
    { question: '馬', answer: ['말 마', 'うま、ま', 'ば'] },
    { question: '魚', answer: ['물고기 어', 'さかな、うお', 'ぎょ'] },
    { question: '鳥', answer: ['새 조', 'とり', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '鳴', answer: ['울 명', 'なく、なる、ならす', 'めい'] },
    { question: '米', answer: ['쌀 미', 'こめ', 'べい、まい'] },
    { question: '麦', answer: ['보리 맥', 'むぎ', 'ばく'] },
    { question: '肉', answer: ['고기 육', '고기', 'にく'] },
    { question: '食', answer: ['밥 식', 'た(べる)、く(う)、くら(う)', 'しょく、[じき]'] },
    { question: '茶', answer: ['차 다(차)', '차', 'さ、ちゃ'] },
    { question: '道', answer: ['길 도', 'みち', 'どう、[とう]'] },
    { question: '毎', answer: ['매양 매', '매양', 'まい'] },
    { question: '週', answer: ['돌 주', '돌', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '朝', answer: ['아침 조', 'あさ', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '昼', answer: ['낮 주', 'ひる', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '夜', answer: ['밤 야', 'よ、よる', 'や'] },
    { question: '時', answer: ['때 시', 'とき', 'じ'] },
    { question: '曜', answer: ['빛날 요', '빛날', 'よう'] },
    { question: '半', answer: ['반 반', 'なか(ば)', 'はん'] },
    { question: '京', answer: ['서울 경', '서울', 'きょう、けい'] },
    { question: '里', answer: ['마을 리', 'さと', 'り'] },
    { question: '会', answer: ['모일 회', 'あ(う)', 'かい、え'] },
    { question: '社', answer: ['모일 사', 'やしろ', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '公', answer: ['공평할 공', 'おおやけ', 'こう'] },
    { question: '園', answer: ['동산 원', 'その', 'えん'] },
    { question: '寺', answer: ['절 사', 'てら', 'じ'] },
    { question: '交', answer: ['사귈 교', 'まじ(わる)、まじ(える)、ま(じる)、ま(ざる)、ま(ぜる)、か(う)、か(わす)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '絵', answer: ['그림 회', '그림', 'かい、え'] },
    { question: '画', answer: ['그림 화', '그림', 'が、かく'] },
    { question: '言', answer: ['말씀 언', 'い(う)、こと', 'げん、ごん'] },
    { question: '語', answer: ['말씀 어', 'かた(る)、かた(らう)', 'ご'] },
    { question: '教', answer: ['가르칠 교', 'おし(える)、おそ(わる)', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '室', answer: ['집 실', 'むろ', 'しつ'] },
    { question: '工', answer: ['장인 공', '장인', 'こう、く'] },
    { question: '作', answer: ['지을 작', 'つく(る)', 'さく、さ'] },
    { question: '計', answer: ['셀 계', 'はか(る)、はか(らう)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '算', answer: ['셈 산', '셈', 'さん'] },
    { question: '点', answer: ['점 점', '점', 'てん'] },
    { question: '数', answer: ['셈 수', 'かず、かぞ(える)', 'すう、[す]'] },
    { question: '読', answer: ['읽을 독', 'よ(む)', 'どく、とく、[とう]'] },
    { question: '書', answer: ['글 서', 'か(く)', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '記', answer: ['기록할 기', 'しる(す)', 'き'] },
    { question: '新', answer: ['새 신', 'あたら(しい)、あら(た)、にい', 'しん'] },
    { question: '聞', answer: ['들을 문', 'き(く)、き(こえる)', 'ぶん、もん'] },
    { question: '番', answer: ['차례 번', '차례', 'ばん'] },
    { question: '組', answer: ['짤 조', 'く(む)、くみ', 'そ'] },
    { question: '歌', answer: ['노래 가', 'うた、うた(う)', 'か'] },
    { question: '声', answer: ['소리 성', 'こえ、[こわ]', 'せい、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '楽', answer: ['노래 악/즐길 락', 'たの(しい)、たの(しむ)', 'がく、らく'] }
  ]
}
